# **SOLA AKINBODE**

+1 403 466-9066 | <u>akinbodesola@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/olusolaakinbode/</u> | <u>www.solaakinbode.com</u> | <u>https://github.com/OAkinbode</u>

### Summary

Software engineering professional with a solid track record of developing diverse applications using a range of tools and languages, including JavaScript, Java, C++, Python, Node.js, Spring Boot, React, React Native, Angular, SQL, Databricks, Docker, Git, GitHub, and MongoDB. Demonstrates exceptional analytical abilities, proficient coding expertise, and excellent oral and written communication skills. Capable of working alone, as part of a team, and on multiple, concurrent projects. Able to thrive in fast-paced, evolving environments and a desire for continuous improvement. Prior experience in energy industry asset management and utilities.

### Experience

#### Resin8.ai

Full Stack (E-commerce) Software Engineer

07/2023 - Present

- Developing an AI-powered e-commerce application for buying and selling industrial and agricultural equipment, targeting a USD 592.4 Billion market.
- *Tech stack:* TypeScript, React.js/Next.js, React Native, Express.js, MongoDB, AWS, OpenAI/AI model integration, payment integration with Stripe, Geolocation with Leaflet.

# Southern Alberta Institute of Technology (SAIT)

Software Development Instructor

01/2024 - Present

- Over 80 students taught to build professional level full stack web applications.
- Over 40 students taught to use open-source AI models in front and backend applications for various use-cases as part of a course on Emerging Technologies.
- Tech stack: React/Next.js, Firebase backend services, FastAPI, Huggingface.io.

### **One Community Global**

Full Stack Software Developer 05/2023 – 08/2023

- Contributed to open-source application for volunteer management for use by over 1000 volunteers.
- *Tech stack:* JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Tailwind, Node.js, and MongoDB with a team of software developers.

### **ENVERUS**

Software Engineering intern 01/2023 – 04/2023

- Developed new microservice to handle authentication workflow for existing application.
  Microservice also enabled integration with third-party authentication and authorization provider.
- **Tech stack:** Angular, Spring Boot, Java EE, AuthO.

# **Onyxworld Itd**

Project Engineer 01/2018 – 09/2019

Managed construction and installation projects to meet scope and budget requirements. Led teams of over 10 professionals and technicians to deliver high-impact solar projects for schools and businesses in Nigeria. Skills included energy data analysis, project management, and construction management.

### **Beacon Power Services**

Project Manager (Energy monitoring and Analysis) 05/2015 – 12/2017

Led a team that developed data analysis and efficiency pipelines for energy industry clients including Utilities such as Ikeja Electric. I led efforts to autonomously collect energy consumption data with sensors and analyze the data in cloud systems. Then, I used that intelligence to generate and execute projects to optimize energy spend by clients. I owned the entire process, and my key deliverable was improving client energy efficiency and reducing costs. Over USD 10 million in energy savings was achieved.

#### **Education and Certifications**

- Master's degree in software engineering, University of Calgary, Canada, 05/2022 04/2023.
- Bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering, University of Agriculture Abeokuta, Nigeria, 05/2005 12/2010.
- Project Management Professional (PMP), Project Management Institute, 07/2020.

### Skills

Java, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Node.js, React, Angular, Spring Boot, MVC, Git/Version Control, GitHub, Docker, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft), MongoDB, Firebase, Databricks, Junit, Project Management, Jira, Product Management, Data analysis, AWS, Stripe Integration.

### Software Development Projects

## Portfolio web application

The portfolio web application showcases both my front-end and back-end web development skills. You can also interact with some of my projects. Visit my portfolio website at: <a href="https://www.solaakinbode.com">www.solaakinbode.com</a>.

### Other software development projects

Explore some of my other projects on GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/OAkinbode?tab=repositories">https://github.com/OAkinbode?tab=repositories</a>.